This is you
or you Hello, welcome all of you to my
new video. In today's video, we
will focus on which
health insurance plan is best for your parents. But
before that, please subscribe to my channel,
like my video and press the bell icon.
I am your help
consultant call. First of all,
in this video, I will tell you
why it is important to take health insurance for your parents. Friends,
as we grow older, the
chances of us falling ill also increase.
But in such a situation, we use the money we have saved to get
our
illness treated. But it is often
seen that people who do
not have the necessary resources, take a loan or
sell their property to get their treatment done, due to
which all our financial
planning gets spoiled.
Keeping this in mind, we should take health insurance.
Now we will talk about
how much cover size we should take in health insurance. Friends, what
we are talking about is normally
for parents and for people between 50 to 70 years of age.  If we are
talking about insurance then the admin
refill is more, the chances of getting sick are
more and the cost of treatment is
also expensive, keeping this in mind
you should try to get maximum health insurance cover for your family
because now friends, if the
risk is high then the premium will also be high,
so you have to see that there is a plan
whose premium is also on the right order for you. There are
two types of plans, individual
and protection. There is a difference between both, let me
tell you this. In individual plan, you are a
citizen news, for example, if there is a
plan of 5 lakhs then you can
use the entire ₹5000 on yourself and in floater
plan, two or more people like
husband and wife, they had
four children, you can avoid this
problem, as you will get a cover of 5 lakhs,
then all the family members
can use some of the covers. In my opinion, you should get a plan
for your parents in which you can
mute only your parents and if
you do not include the children in it then  It will be
better for you as a floater plan is
also cheaper than an individual plan.
While choosing a company, you have to keep in mind that there are
two types of settlements.
Normally, one is CSR (Plain
Settlement Ratio) and the second is ICR.
CSR is normally used in life insurance companies,
which shows
how many people's claims the company has settled. Finally,
if the claim settlement ratio of a company is
90%, then it is believed that the company is very good in
settling people's claims and the higher
this figure is, the
better it is for you. The second one is
ICRA (Good Impression Ratio) which is
used in normal health insurance companies.
It means how much the company has
collected from your policy and how much
love it has given you. Suppose a
company has collected ₹100 and it has given you one for ₹10,
we will
not consider that company to be a very good company and the
stability of that company will also be less, the company whose
review is 50 and  If the age limit is between 60 and
70, then that company is considered good, it means that the
company is capable of giving it to you.
Now before you go for the policy, you also have to keep in
mind that the company is giving you life
insurance because friends, if your
age increases and the company
refuses to renew your policy, then it can be a
problem for you, so you should
take such a plan where you get life insurance and life
insurance. After this comes the
waiting period. We are
talking about people of this age group, their age group.
Normally it has been found that people already have
many diseases like BP, sugar,
thyroid, so you have to keep in mind that when you
tell such diseases to the company, then
how much waiting period does the company impose on you. The
minimum number of meeting minutes will be the
benefit for you. Now it
comes to the claim, but what is the payment to you?
Payment means if your
claim is of Rs 1 lakh and the company has
set a payment of Rs 20 lakh for you,
then you have to pay Rs 20,000 from your office
or keep one thing in mind.  How to
choose the company's plan for you, where the
payment is minimal or no, it will be
more beneficial for you. After this
comes the free and post-graduation rehearsal
edition. When you are getting
your treatment done at home before going to the hospital,
all your expenses are also completely
covered. It is called free
hospitalization. And when
you are getting your treatment done at home after coming from the hospital, it is
called Hathras Junction. So
keep in mind that under Free and Prosperous Nation,
you are covered for maximum expenses.
After this, let's go here.
Seriously, now see what are the famous
treatments in which the patient does
not need to be admitted to the hospital.
Their treatment is done in less than 24 hours.
For example, nowadays there are many services
which are curable within 2 hours,
like getting an operation done through laser surgery. So,
you should keep in mind that when will all such
famous buses increase in your policy?
Now we will talk about its charges during this period. The
company
puts charges in its plant for a particular disease,
so you should keep this in mind.  You should make sure to
use a branch where you don't have any complaints.
After this comes emergency ambulance.
Emergency charges vary from one bank to another,
so you need to check
how much the company is paying you in ambulance charges. Now we will talk about the
types of companies that
operate in the market. One is life
insurance companies, which include Life Insurance
of India, also known as LIC of India,
Max Life Insurance, HDFC
Life, ICICI Prudential, SBI Life.
Apart from this, there are many other companies that
deal only in life insurance. The
other company is
called general insurance. These
companies, apart from life insurance, offer all types
of insurance, such as health
insurance, travel insurance, car
insurance, and Fire Shot. The
prominent names in this are Bajaj Alliance, some
public undertakings complete, such as United
India Insurance, New India Insurance,
and Oriental Insurance. There are also companies
that sell only health insurance,
such as Max Bupa Health Insurance,
HDFC Ergo Health Insurance, Relige
Health Insurance, and Star Health
Insurance. Apart from this, there are many other companies.  There are
around 34 such health insurance companies in total
and they have many different plans
for you friends it is a very difficult task to do complete
research on so many
and know about all the types of plans
and that too is difficult to see this thing
I also did a lot of research and then only
I
made a video for you now I will
tell you which health insurance plan you should take for your parents
after proper search I have found
five such plans for your parents
which will give benefits to your parents and they
are Religare Care Senior Plan Religare
Care Freedom From Four Senior Citizen Red
Carpet Line and Maths Fufa Help Companies
Plan now there is another plan which I would
like to mention and it is Apollo Munich Optima
Senior and now the name of this plan has become
SSC Al Gore Health Optimus Senior Friend
these five plans which I have
told you the names of these companies are the best for your parents that
means you must take them for your parents
and they will be anxious because
their health
insurance policy will take care of their health for them
if you liked this information  So please
share it with me in the comment box. If you want, you
can also connect with me through WhatsApp. Agarwal friends, if
you have not yet subscribed to my channel, then
please subscribe to my channel
and like my videos and press the bell icon
because friends, this
motivates me and you also
remain updated with my latest videos. Thank you for
watching our video. I
like it.